man hello Spencer welcome to the virtual
remote version of the junkyard love bot
yes
yes I think is the first time we have
video you know yeah yeah we haven't done
video yet eventually it'd be nice to
have video right right freaking here
that's the plan but things are a bit
there's a bit of a wrench in the system
as it may
with the coronavirus so we're making do
with what we have here so you coming to
me virtually even though we're not super
far away no no we're not I will say one
disclaimer I have a cat he likes to sit
on my laptop so he's gonna poke in every
once in a while that's a good these are
these are just the things I was
listening to I was listening to this
thing I think it was Jordan Hall was
talking or answering some Q&A stuff on
on on his YouTube but he was essentially
they were talking about like as they're
trying to pay attention this is a new
thing like so if you had a plumber over
like I can hear that through and as much
as I'm trying to focus on the content of
what you're saying like you can't ignore
the fact that you like are really like
so on like so you have to almost work a
little bit harder but I think it's
probably something that we can like the
more that people do this sort of remote
like conversation through through our
computers and our and our phones and
stuff the FaceTime sort of way I think
that we'll be able to like way easier
just be like oh that's a sound that I'm
not paying attention to so I don't have
to worry about it you know but as it as
it is now we're like very like oh we're
very we're like we hear something on
background and we're annoyed by it are
we it's distraction easily yeah I found
myself especially if I haven't been like
super mindful super annoyed by small
distractions right yeah because it has
been I basically I spent the first
couple weeks just playing xbox and lying
around and I'm so irritable like I
flipped my sleep schedule back around I
feel a lot better but dude why'd you
become irritable you think like quick
wedding they're calling into it just by
being at home uh no I did not being at
home I think it's just a sleep schedule
you know when you wake up at noon you
just don't wake up really yeah then
you're like hyper sense
of all day but not in like a good
awesome way like a not a good way you
know it's like starting your day with a
late start I did that working at the
lumber mill for five years I was on the
same shift where I didn't wake up to
11:30 a.m. every day and it's like this
inevitable like almost anxiety type
feeling that you feel like you wake up
and like 11:30 is okay that's six and a
half seven hours of sleep like that's
not that's like waking up early as far
as other people are concerned but in
your head in your body and like the way
that the world has momentum already the
society has momentum like everybody like
doctor's appointments have come and gone
for other people like you wake up and
you're just like no matter what like
what the reason like whether you're
laying around being being a turret or
whether you're like like going to work
or whether you're just like you don't
have anything else to do because we're
on quarantine it still kind of makes you
feel man when you sleep into it I felt
like that I felt it was like eight
o'clock I'm like damn I didn't even get
to do anything today I don't get
anything done even though I had nothing
to get done you know I was still like
that looming feeling of right it's not
productive we assign ourselves like dude
you didn't do anything today like cuz
sometimes you got to just like live life
like you got to be able to put the
momentum of everything on pause and just
have a day where it's like dude I didn't
wake up until when the hell ever that's
fine you got to be able to let yourself
have this for sure it's not every day I
suppose yeah I kind of went from working
from like well is that a house from like
6:00 to 8:00 every single day to the
last day of school was the first day of
quarantine so and I don't I'm not
working now so I went from 14 hours of
work to no hours of anything it was just
and it made me really empathize with
people that live like that anyways like
normally like people just kind of like
lay around they wake up relay this stay
up real late and they just like don't
exercise dude I feel horrible there yeah
you just gotta I feel like it kind of
gave me to inside to like a lot of
people's lives not just that sucks yeah
it's hard to pry yourself away from that
feeling like it feels like such like a
like a permanent lethargy that you're
just so used to in your everyday life
and it's hard to like gain that moment
like okay get back in the gym get back
in a routine get back and waking up
early like wanting to feel better cuz
it's so easy to just veg out not do this
thing yeah there's like a certain amount
of resistance whenever you go do
anything that's like good for you like
I've been trying to read a book for
quite a while and I just didn't have
time to during the quarter like for
school
but like I sat down multiple times in
those weeks of just like not doing
anything to to read it and I'm like no
no I came to this that's like you just
momentum is definitely a real thing
because when I'm on did it you always
get wavy to done this has been such a
weird time because I don't know about
you but I just don't do well with at
least a little structure like just being
like hey you have six weeks to do
nothing what are you gonna do and I
don't know I don't know what other
people are doing but right yeah I think
it I think it might be time to you work
on some habits I guess because I've
heard it takes twenty to thirty days to
change habits or create habits might be
a good time so I'm not doing any better
right cool yeah I like that I like where
your head's going I think a lot of
people are kind of like that they've
done enough hours of Netflix and
scrolling to the phones they're probably
like to him like I think I'm gonna
probably do that too I just feel like
perhaps we're we're getting there so uh
let's direct so for anybody who has
never heard any of our previous podcast
knows nothing of your background I would
like to ask your advice or your maybe
recommendations or maybe a broad
spectrum of things that people could be
trying I'm just thinking of everybody at
home everybody needs to use to be
stretching they need to get some form of
working out they need to get some fresh
air they need to be mindful like all
these little things that might be
obvious to to perhaps me or of course
you like what can we you know kind of
put a flare up about as far as what's
important for like what
what people should be paying attention
to at this time why should they be
actively doing just for wellness in
general like peace of mind just fitness
yeah I suppose and if there's things
that people need that I'm not covering
that that I'm not saying definitely
cover that too if there's things that
you are seeing like may be interacting
with more people are having more people
around you maybe you're seeing things
that people need that I'm not so also
open court honestly so your body runs on
like an internal clock that really
depends on you going to sleep on waking
up at a pretty consistent time I against
what I've done I mean I got my say to go
back together but staying maintaining
like I go to bed at 11:00 wake up at
7:00 sleep schedule is gonna help your
sets of well-being a lot and your body
is just gonna function a lot better so
that's one of the easiest things you can
do I mean because it's like if you're
gonna be up for 16 hours no matter what
you might as well just shift it back
that's easy that's really easy working
out to Ronda I'd do anything for that
but I would say definitely try to sweat
everyday somehow I don't care what looks
like like cleaning laundry do whatever
you need to do just move because I mean
a lot of people have always said like a
body in motion stays in motion so when
you just kind of especially if you've
already been in the fitness you just
stop moving like you're gonna feel like
[__] you know I think very well like
your sense of well-being it's gonna be
pretty down mm-hmm so I mean in body
weight workouts people I've seen people
bashing on the internet like oh you're
not gonna get what you want but you're
gonna get something and from all the
science I've ever seen you're gonna hold
on to like anyway you're gonna maintain
fitness level if you're already fit and
if you haven't been working out it's a
good time to start because no one's
gonna judge you in your house go into
another room like this is a this is the
great equalizer for fitness you know
like every fit person now has to take
you two months off so if you want to get
on it we're all doing bodyweight squats
right well let's so let's let's talk
about those people who will start at the
ground level where people who like
really don't know [__] about working out
like they admitted ly they're like I
don't know anything about working out
but like let's do it I know it's gonna
be better for mental health my physical
health whatever what would be some
recommendations I think the first thing
that I would say is stretching
stretching super important to me but I
think that there's there's so many
different facets in so many different
ways to like be active like or or just
be moving your body like even just
moving your neck around and your
eyeballs in your face like there's so
many little things that that could
benefit just movement practice oh well
what do you got what would you recommend
to people who are trying to get off the
ground
well stretch is not a bad place to start
I mean most people sight pain as a
reason I exercise and I mean I'm just
reading like a plane for eight hours of
sat down for a long time you get really
stiff like there's there's tissue in
between your muscle fibers it's like
kind of a liquid and kind of a solid and
when you don't move for a while it gets
really hard you stiffen up so when you
start moving again it gets all slighty
and nice so just like waking up in
stretching how we see fit honestly
you're not gonna hurt yourself whatever
you want to do just like no headstand
probably good
but just do what feels good mmm like to
definitely remember to breathe as well
but yeah I would say for fitness stuffs
like start with don't do anything crazy
stick to the basics like bodyweight
squats I would seek awake movements and
at least for a little while you can get
a lot out of them right what do you do
what's your at home like a workout like
so you obviously go to the gym but what
if you were not able to and you're like
I got a work at home what would your
situation be like we lift up water jugs
like what like where you at
oh for sure buy some bands with
different strength intentions like so on
Amazon there's like it's just like five
bands you can clip on two handles and
that'll pretty much get you everything
you need honestly I mean like anything
that that's not going to do for you or
you can't do with bodyweight is probably
not super necessary right now so
but without weight if you have not been
exercising just stick to bodyweight
stuff it's gonna be enough but if you
have been exercising
I would really shoot like because you
can't load so heavy I would like go to
failure like make it just make it really
intense because you just need to have an
intensifying technique like you can
either do a lot of reps to really heavy
or doing really frequently like you
can't do them really heavy but you can
do these other two so you can do
bodyweight squats every day or every
other day and you can do a lot of them
very intensely like you don't like not
everything needs to be super heavy and
the whole like marriage to heavy weight
is I even when I'm at the gym I don't
think that's really the case so like you
can you can get way more out of just how
much you weigh we went at around mmm
than people think
yeah I totally agree like you can do so
much with your body we calculate
everything you know like I always think
I used to be so caught up and like the
amount of reps and like making sure I
would always like hit exactly ten
exactly ten on this side and just like
okay well I know that I exactly started
with with 45 last week when I was on
this muscle so I got to go to this and I
think that that thinking a little more
broad about our health right now is is
important like just just like who cares
how much you could vent right now who
cares so much she could away right now
or how much you weigh right now like
just think about like you're sitting
around more you're in sunshine a lot
less like think about what you can do
maybe not to maintain every ounce of
gains or progress or whatever wherever
you were but rather just to try to find
a new version of a healthy while at home
here yeah I think that um this is an
awesome time to get a good all the [__]
that you're not good at you've been
neglecting no like mindfulness breath
work flexibility cardio like all the
stuff that people are like huh some
other time like doing what else are you
doing
like now these things take wait so you
do in your bedroom like this is a really
good time like I started doing cardio
again started meditating like way more
rapidly than I was and started get back
into breath work and it's been really
nice do you notice you noticed a
difference you notice you're kind of
like like fighting off the irritability
more you're feeling like you're kind of
in grasp and in control a bit more or
when I meditate for well I you always
meditate but just not for long periods
of time like usually five minutes so
through five minutes the morning I've
just always done that but when I start
to do for like 10 20 I noticed that I'm
Way less irritable and you just the
amount of presents that you have it's
just much better and it's almost as like
like if negativity or things that would
irritate you are like water you're just
like covered in oil like you see it come
at you and it kind of bounces off you're
like well yeah you really can't affect
me right but if I'm not not doing that
it uh I'm super irritable normally like
as a person before I got any of it
extremely irritable right you know I
think the one thing that I think that's
gonna come up a lot in this particular
situation when everybody's locked in is
it's so abrupt it
before being mindful there is a step
there's a step before being mindful and
that is awareness I think how do people
become aware that like instead of saying
that's just me anybody who would be mad
in the situation anybody's like look
what's going on in my life here's why
it's setup justifying why they're mad or
why they're irritated or why they're
like why they were the one who just won
the silly argument with them and they're
left alone who are just too closed right
now for too long like how do how do we
become aware before becoming mindful
well that's kind of rough I mean I don't
know if you can like really will people
out of ignorance it seems to be kind of
a natural thing that happens but I'm
definitely more experienced with this
and I do I mean I can only speak to my
own personal journey really it's just
just like kind of start to pay attention
to stuff and all of a sudden oh wow like
maybe this is the way I am isn't
necessarily a solid statement right yeah
I think of you to start observing the
way that you do things and like now more
than ever we're kind of like we can't
distractions have out there we're kind
of just like forced to take a look at
like okay what are my habits right now
and like what do those reflect and what
do i what do I want from those habits I
think just taking a look your habits I
think we've talked before about just
like make an example we've used was even
just opening the door handle with your
left hand rather than your right hand or
something like that just those little
things where it's like you kind of just
put a little wedge in what you normally
do just enough to where you can stop and
say like doing this do I want to be
doing this what what's the outcome of me
doing this thing and you could just
start to like oh okay now that I'm
noticing now that I'm aware of this
thing I can watch myself do it next time
and maybe make a different decision or
whatever good tying your
moment-to-moment actions to outcomes
it's probably very hopeful I mean I
guess if I don't do that I will just
I mean do only sloth-like Abbot's cuz
that's like my natural state if I'm not
paying attention you just kind of like
brush off all important stuff and you
just kind of lay around but want to pay
attention to that this doesn't happen so
yeah who doesn't want to be safe in
their cave it was good dude it does feel
good
but it doesn't actually feel good long
run at all yeah so mindfulness give
people who are at home who don't know
[__] about mindfulness who like they're
going they're convinced enough that they
should probably practicing mindfulness
but they don't know like really where to
start where would you suggest anybody
start trying to be mindful how does your
mind assert hyper analyzing you you're
yourself and what you do like do art
like just what do you do and why do you
do it why do you do it is the important
one it's like I do I sure I do a bunch
of stuff and everyone does a bunch stuff
they don't really know why they do
except analyze it yet but once you start
doing that you're like okay maybe I
shouldn't be doing this maybe this is
not actually out for all right that's a
good place to start it doesn't have to
be rooted in like any it would like
people call like like woo spiritualness
like this is just purely analyzing who
you are and what you do and what the
outcomes of the star and instead of just
like rushing headlong through your life
and doing stuff for you to like actually
make a decision what you're gonna do
because we just are kind of full crater
just like this instinct habitual stuff
that we all do and most people don't
think about it I would start there
yeah cool I agree yeah I think that we
don't we don't really like take a look
at at what we're doing but again we're
kind of forced to you right now there's
a lot of people that are like you know
like I said we're not able to keep
scrolling and Cree and keep just
watching the same news and keep having
like the the kind of like fake semi
drama to talk about to fill our times
with like you know if you can have some
sort of like silly reality TV show to
talk about for six hours a day if you
really wanted to but now it's kind of
like there's this like Oh
that's not super important is it I think
that's an obvious feeling within
everybody right now you know yeah
everybody's kind of just like looking
for like where do I I point that
attention waiting back at them so yeah
I'm sure everyone's run out of stuff
when every feet about resourceful maybe
yep they have and then like did you know
you can actually get to the effing its
Instagram I think you could actually get
to the end there's an end of it really
yeah I don't know how absolute that is
but I had Shane Lee told me one of her
friends got to the end one day scrolling
disagreeing on like well I am that is
that's a law scrolling yeah like what
what is that like just over the course
of me pulling out my phone and now like
I scroll I looked at everything within
the last few days that everybody posted
besides when I first started that's not
that too even though that's it that's a
lot of time this stuff like I've
scrolled for a while and that not even
close I don't like so looking at
scrolling like why do we even scroll
like why do we want to know like what
people are doing and what's like
brand-new in the in their life you know
over you know of course it's nice to
know like what your friends are up to
its nicely keep updated on people's why
snowy families up to but why do we
choose that over taking care of
ourselves and like doing even even just
simple things like like ma'am you know I
always did want to play guitar like why
why are you choosing to scroll right now
rather than pick up that guitar that's
in the back of the room you know what I
mean like you seeing that I think it's
important I just don't think that people
will even scroll to see how other
people's lives are actually like I don't
think most people like it dude if you
follow eight hundred people do you
really give a [__] about most of their
lives I mean like abstractly like as a
human being to human being I hope
they're really doing well but you're not
actually personally best for these
people right you're just bored and this
is not this is not enjoying it's just
satiating like kinda it's just this is
like scratching an itch that will never
go away like this is just it's such an
easy activity to do when you have
nothing to do and it requires is little
to no thought
I think that's what we will do it
because like all these other things okay
learn how to play guitar well that's
hard
and that requires vulnerability and
looking at Instagram does not at all and
it's right here it's just I think it's
just too accessible cuz I like singing
good I was looking at my phone I'm like
- I don't even have this I do not care
what is on this at all like I was like I
don't even I felt like 500 people in
every page that isn't a person I just
like I do I even like this might even
interested in this you know why do I use
this
right this was after like seven to eight
days of just playing xbox and sitting on
social media I'm like dude hey I'm so
tired of this stuff cuz this just is not
fulfilling well so do you think there's
do you think there's people who I don't
know aren't going to be able to realize
that they're like okay it's been it's
been it's been in seven days it's been
this many days like do you think they're
just like prepping to go on to week two
of the exact same thing yes Mahavir son
the 40-minute to time limit on your
group meeting well that's fun
Thanks I am yeah I think walk do you
some people are drinking everyday like
people are the problem is if you'd have
vices and you run out like who you are
not in your routine anymore they will
just Nick at you right like - definitely
sloth and it definitely consumed me for
like ten days yeah when it doesn't do
anything it'll just lay around play
games that's it I mean it was kind of
nice because I've been working so much
but it also is just not I mean I can see
how people would fall in a very
destructive habits if it's not checked
right so so what do you what are you
gonna do now I feel like I
I'm battle I battle my own ways but I
feel like I've I've been able to
establish quite a decent routine like I
even before like the quarantine thing
and just kind of live the isolated
solitude introverted life up here what
I'm not traveling I'm coming just making
a work from home situation work so I
have my own ways of making sure I go for
a run and make sure I go outside there's
things that have changed obviously and
can change further because of the
quarantine but um I know I think I have
quite a few ways you know like you
mentioned breath work and meditation and
planning at night and in the morning
running all these sort of things
what so you mentioned that you had been
slothy are you feeling less slothy are
you feeling like yeah I know it's okay
so it was actually spring break like I
had probably yeah so I got the best GP
I've ever got in school like I've been
working more than I've ever worked and
taking that week was actually just nice
like I didn't feel bad about it I felt
it was like it was earned but after like
a week
it was just not helpful anymore it just
felt bad like I didn't feel bad about it
I felt like I'm not airing this this is
nice this is a nice time to relax but so
today I got up at 7 instead of 12
and 8a I've basically started control
the controllables so I like a plant out
my whole diet find out on my training
because or my family owns a gym so I can
still I still get exercise so planned
out on my training and then I'm just
gonna hammer that because it's something
I could really focus on and I'm probably
start journaling I haven't been doing
that something I've actually never
really got into but I feel like I just
have a lot of time to just kind of sit
and think which what's your what's your
ideas for journaling right now like what
do you think you're gonna start with I
think I just sit down the bullet point
or what I probably just like free pose
it honestly just like sit down or
whatever I feel like is the most just
for whatever it profound that I think or
not even that just anything becomes a
lot no there's no URI on yeah is it like
like sometimes I'll make myself start
with something because I just like I
have so many ideas or the lack of ideas
that make sense and I just gotta be like
dude just put a little dot at the top of
the page and start a bullet point and
just write whatever one sentence even if
the rest of the piece of paper has
nothing to do with that first sentence
or it's like 17 different thoughts like
that's okay I think just getting it out
there cuz sometimes you'll look at a
piece of paper after you just wrote
you're like oh [__] I didn't know I
thought I knew that stuff you don't know
what you think about until you think
about it you know mm-hmm yeah and
thoughts are so fleeting to like dude I
wish that I would take voice memos more
or what have for the last like five
years and I think of anything that I
enjoy you always will forget I think
that just controlling the controllables
right now is gonna be the most important
part of just feeling satisfied and not
frightened because it's like the world
is insane currently and everyone's life
has been shaken up and if you just don't
well you're just gonna have to control
only what you can you can't worry about
anything else just notice that it's just
a person is really smart intelligent
like well-thought-out rational being but
people are really dumb and panicky and
we're coming together to be people
hmm we need to be a person I think that
a yeah an individual because people like
it to you I don't know if you've been on
social media lately but people are like
one person it just takes one one fool in
the group of many people that aren't
foolish to panic and know everyone is
panicking mmm right so what do you what
are you seeing on social media like from
an outside perspective of people will
baby self sabotaging themselves like
because obviously a consumption of the
wrong media a consumption of news about
the coronavirus or even just crappy news
about it
any news about it is obviously bad but I
think that people even with like
self-deprecating memes and just like
liking hateful tweets about it or like I
don't know I think there's a lot that we
do to ourselves that we don't realize we
think it's just making us laugh and it's
just entertainment but I think that it
actually harms us what are you seeing on
social media well I mean I just think
that it's been it's very sensational
right now and there's like blasting the
death toll every day and it's I'm sure
it affects people psyche quite a lot
just to see this happening and then also
people just I think you I would assume
that in a time of one of the greatest
vulnerabilities that I have ever seen in
my whole life that people would stop
pooping on each other like kind of rally
and gain some empathy for everyone
situation like hey man this is this is
affecting everyone but uh just never
stopped the internet hate and I would
say just stop using Twitter just just
get off
just just get off your ducking raft man
dude get off Twitter on Facebook like
you can go to some nice quiet hole and
read it with only nice people you can
find a community for that but Facebook
and Twitter are hot garbage
I've got I've got a good idea one that I
would so this is kind of what I did I
feel like when I quit my social media
I'm back full force now I'm totally like
addicted to the stupid thing again
freaking Instagram but um but so I had
quit for a year but what I did is I feel
like I kind of like traded
addictions in a weird way like I just
started massively being on YouTube like
I said [__] scram [__] Facebook don't
follow anybody that you know who cares
like you're going to talk to your
friends that you're already group
messaging otherwise like the people who
like if somebody really wants to talk to
you on snapchat like they're going to
have your number like you say it doesn't
matter
I think getting rid of these things or
even taking like a few day break and be
a week break 10 day break you're not
gonna die you're not gonna burst into
flames and just fill all that time when
you do pick up your phone instead of
just because it's kind of hard to do all
the sudden cold turkey or addictions
even if it is just the silly phone but
to just get on there and start like
watching interesting stuff have a
headphone in I don't know I think
Trading creating your social media
additions to YouTube or some other
positive something app what do you think
about that do youtube is actually on all
my time yeah my dad it's not really the
actual social apps it's just watching
YouTube so I'm really watching it it's
more it's just always in the background
playing which is also not great because
you just don't get time to think about
stuff because I know is this how I know
that I've been in taking way too much
media so we come home from work I'm
about a 15-minute drive oh you know I'm
not gonna listen anything I'll set my
phone down and it's just thought thought
thought and they're all important it's
like all [__] that I should have been
thinking about that are like of great
importance to me and I just haven't been
because I've just been watching eight
hours of YouTube a day right yeah so I
think there there's a place for silence
as well but it's definitely you can make
YouTube a lot less hateful than Twitter
Twitter is one of the vilest places I've
ever been
it is like the butthole of the internet
yeah it's funny I watched this I heard
something or watch this essentially
somebody was talking about like the
language that you can say on the
Internet versus like let alone real life
but Facebook so say Twitter on Twitter
you can be like I'm gonna hate myself
and people are like yeah but [__] laugh
bro like they're like commenting and
then I'm on Facebook if you said I'm
[__] to hate myself like grandma be
like are you okay this is devastating
like what's going on like and then in
real life like it's kind of the same
thing like certain situations you
and just be like crazy self-deprecating
or like like vulgar and every like like
because Twitter just pushes right to the
edge of like like you're allowed to say
that or like you're that's really what
we're talking about okay like it's just
it's it's it's hilariously funny often
that for sure
but it's mostly too much of just
bite-sized entertainment and you can't
really get a ton of entertainment in
bite-size form in a clean format so
after a while it's just in a thoughtful
format it doesn't have to be clean it's
just not thoughtful or creative it's
just haha life bad won't die like you
know like it's just not it's not funny
and I honestly think that it's just it's
just a dimers it's our generation you
know like we got pushed into a world
that's pretty much a hell world and no
systems in place function at all and we
didn't really we had the internet so we
didn't have to really eat all the
propaganda that is being fed got fed to
like our parents right so yeah like we
have no so like in the world is
literally on fire Australia's yeah first
six months out of the year so I
understand what we were like feel like
that but it's just not helpful yeah I
don't think gosh well gotcha so
interesting to think about the fact that
like like as our parents are like
watching like they're still we're
walking past them on the couch as
they're like watching like the same
media and we're like you don't have to
watch that and they're like no no you do
okay and we like walk into the kitchen
we get our laptops for like 10 years and
we're just like learning about how the
world really works as they're just
listening to how the world is working
according to whoever is making the rules
for them to think about [__] yeah okay
so every major news outlet is owned by
the same like few companies that all
essentially work together mm-hmm so it
feels like one it's just like one one
agenda talking to all these people and
it's just not uh it's not helpful if you
watch corporate media stop its act it is
just propaganda there's no way around
I'd like oh I know you love I love your
hosts but most of them are like see or
or like on the board of banks like trust
fund kid like these people are not like
they're not your friend really like they
just want to profit off you so it's bad
don't adjust it it's literally like
brain poison you want to get news like
go to some third party go to youtube go
find someone you like this independent
stuff stop watching that because it is
just going to scare you and it's not
good for your brain right I think the
the we're like so for me awareness when
I was mentioning earlier in being
mindful avoid consuming so like I had
been excessively consuming like for
there was a couple days where I was like
I'm not stressed honestly like I'm fine
I'm not like freaking out about it but I
was excessively consuming it but I was
consuming like long-form videos of like
biologists talking about the long-form
systemic you know like what things are
gonna look like I'm just like learning
about like this broad form of it and I
was like well this is fine it's safe I'm
not like learning about like the dooms
like this is just thinking about
possibilities this thing about what's
next but then I start to notice like
after like three days of just a lot of
that I would wake up it will come fourth
day or whatever it was and I was like
hmm feeling like kind of naturally
despairing I know like I was like I
don't really have like a big pep in my
step and or a lot of like hope to pursue
my dreams today at do I just something I
guess I'm gonna keep listening to those
and it's just it kind of like it kind of
steals your thoughts without you really
noticing you know a lot of the times
when we're just constantly consuming
those things and we just we turn it
right back on if we're not careful so
yeah I ingest way too much news media
like independent news media but just
just in general like I stay away too on
top of like how the world is and it's
just not helpful so what is that
it doesn't have to be bad news
to be bad for you no oh it's just too
much and it's also I realized that will
you watch eight hours YouTube a day
you're ingesting way more information
than you can actually hold on to when it
still affects how you feel so it's like
not only is this super negative
information I'm not gonna remember it
it's just affecting my mood so it's not
helpful right for me like I guess some
people might enjoy it but I can't do any
more yeah dude it depends like if that's
the thing is you got to just start like
choosing what content you're consuming
like yeah maybe it is enjoyable to watch
like your favorite people on your
favorite TV show again or like a new TV
show the hottest TV show your all your
favorite movies like there is times for
that but I feel like setting that as
like it lets only watch TV at night and
like not saying that you don't have to
stay completely away from technology all
the time if that's not your job but make
it to where like throughout the day if
you're not working or you're not doing
something you're not just laying on the
couch so I think like walking around
like kind of like listening to something
like maybe you not even watching it like
as you're working out as you're doing
laundry consume some good content not
just not just like background music or
the news or or the office for the 25th
time which you know I don't blame you
but and I want to talk about breath work
and stretching do you have experience
and breath work on stretching you do to
be honest so one of the once you kick it
off what are you what do you perhaps I
do wim HOF breathing primarily I do a
lot of breath work in general just
because yoga introduces just and just
Prom pranayama kind of just like
introduces familiarity with breathing
and like how it's connected to your body
and so I feel like I've at this point
breath work is is important to me but
it's not like a separate thing than what
I do in my daily life like when I wake
up in the mornings I do some stretches
like before I even go take a leak like I
set I unplug my phone and I set it down
and then like before I get changed into
like you know my like walk around and
close
or whatever it is like I'd start
stretching kinda like breathing and
sending breath in so it eventually
becomes like a very normal thing it
might seem kind of weird to do breath
work now like if you saw somebody just
sitting on the ground breathing in and
out like with a timer in front of them
you'd be like what the [__] like it just
seems weird but it's certainly not after
you just get used to it and realize it's
only weird someone else's opinion but um
I do wim HOF breathing doing it not
every single day but I would say
probably at least four times a week I
just did like literally actually before
this podcasts I did three rounds of 30
and so wim HOF breathing you could look
it up at any listener you can look it up
on the interwebs it's on YouTube he has
a free app you can learn anything about
him like there's just all over just
check out YouTube wim HOF wim HOF F and
so essentially you you get very present
and you stay focused and you breathe in
through your belly and breathe up into
your chest
you and it has like a certain sequence
like an in-out in-out and you keep that
going for 30 rounds and it's not like
the 30 as a magical number when you hit
30 like the heavens of the gates open up
it's not really like that just following
on the apps 30 rounds then you let your
breath out and when your air is emptied
you hold your breath in here is where
you're able to hold your breath for a
lot longer than you think you can you do
a couple more rounds of these end up at
the end of you holding your breath you
breathe back in and hold that for 15
more seconds and then you restart around
so probably over explaining it really
but breath work is is fantastic it
really works to like help me keep
focused yet present helps me like let go
of a lot of the the muscles that I'm
didn't realize that I was tensing up I
personally my my breath work when I do
my wim HOF breathing it's right before
my runs I would not recommend that I
think we've had this discussion before I
don't recommend doing wim HOF breathing
before you run - just like her per
treatment block oh yeah I've you know I
have a familiarity with your own body
and your own mental like I've been
pushing myself to these edges for a long
time it's not like weird to me it's
I know when I'm in a blackout but yeah I
like to do it before I go on a run and
it really helps me mentally lock into my
run and there's so many other benefits
of the breathwork
nice yeah but what about you what's uh
so I every single morning well I don't
always do when I'm operating in the
morning but I will
somedays I combine it with cold showers
and it's more it's not necessarily it's
more of a utilitarian function I used to
wake up because it both cold showers and
wim HOF both to jack up your endorphins
and adrenaline so you wake up because I
just this how I trained myself be a
morning person was just like okay we
start getting up and I started doing
these like really hyper stimulating like
breathing techniques like sometimes I'll
be like fire breathing's or dragon's
breath which is like a really hard
diaphragmatic breath and um it requires
a lot of like a lot of core and
diaphragm control and it almost looks
like just somebody's hyperventilating
but like I assure you it's much more
definitely YouTube it I actually
initially got into breath work to would
just be stronger like I started focusing
on just controlling my diaphragm in the
weight room and that was like wow doing
this has made me much more powerful like
this maybe there's something to it and
then I got into the more like one on the
side of it but I used one hot breathing
mostly just as a tool to get up and
it'll wake you up real quick you want to
be really clear really fast that's a
good form of breath work I recommend
some simple counts of breath work to my
clients who like deal with anxiety or
sometimes I'll run live streams on like
our gym page and I'll like running
through like a really simple breath work
I usually like for 46 so in for for
hopeful for out for six like after
people exercise to like calm down their
nervous system because you usually want
to get in like a healing calming stayed
after you exercise it's not good to be
all riled up for that long so and then
when people are trying to sleep I do in
for four
hold for six out for seven and that
should calm you down and what a bit
really yeah you know it's funny and I
feel like you could probably back me up
on this or tell me your experience but I
feel like with Rapp work it's one of
those things where if you can just get
yourself to do it you'll realize like
there's nobody like you can be ticked
off you can be like your heart rates
elevated and if you just do the breath
work like if you just alright I know
you're irritated man I know you're like
hyper like I know you're like all amped
up right now but just take the time and
do do the you know five in five hour for
four sets or whatever whatever breath
work it is it's like inevitable at the
end they're gonna have a little smirk on
their face like okay I get that
it's an info for hopeful for out four
six is what I do whenever I feel like if
I ever feel anxious or upset or like
riled up in any way or like I need to
think when I'm to in like a state of
like anger or well it just in a non
opportunist aid it always works in the
fun thing about breath is that we evil
literally you can win every state that
you want to bring about you can do it
you can use breath to bring about like
you want really amped up you can do that
you can raise your heart rate you want
to slow down you could also do that yeah
it's like this is a free tool that
everyone does but nobody utilizes it's
Frank yeah you know pay for it like he's
doing YouTube and like figure how to
breathe yeah dude it's an incredible - I
feel like we don't use it very often
just because it's weird like that's
that's what it is I mean think about I
think about working out in the 1800's
like working out like if you saw
somebody you know people obviously
probably didn't like work out with a
dumbbell back then if you saw somebody
just perfectly like having their arm at
their side just lifting it up and down
doing a bicep curl
with some sort of weight you'd be like
what is that weird guy doing and you
wouldn't even know to compare into a
robot because you wouldn't see robots
back then yeah the funny thing is dude
weightlifting is inherently breathwork
like it's this part of it like dude if
you exercise like you just engage in
this and this is honestly this is my
personal theory there's no science
backing this but I feel like when people
run the reason that they like it so much
is because they're finally breathing die
phonetically for hey yeah
like people are actually brief like
that's why it's such a potent stress
reliever also like Xers
Dorf ensue that too but i think a big
part of it is like people are you're
finally breathing you're not shallow
breathing and your posture is probably
better than it usually is because you're
running which posture is actually a
really big part of doing something I
wanted to talk about today like why we
suck acid we're eating normally like
people have terrible breathing veterans
like I knew I mean years are probably
pretty good better than most but like we
just mine used to be really bad we just
have had bad posture for so long almost
everyone that are and nobody talks about
breath like I'm teaching a breathing
school like it is just you know should
have not agreed but do you really though
and once you get the classic hips tilted
shoulders forward hips through like
hunkered down round back posture and
look where your rib cages mm-hm it's
just caving in on itself so I'm gonna
never get this that big and this can
affect like cognitive ability like you
can have so I read a study that when
they fix people's breath work all the
occasions or knots in their back went
away and like two months mmm like maybe
people like all this upper back shoulder
and neck pain that people have just
because we breathe like [__]
I really think good dude I I'm with you
on there I'm huge about about breathing
correctly like it's it's it's such a
it's such a profound thing in it also I
think that it has a lot to do honestly
breathing has a lot to do with posture
for me I feel like it's actually really
closely related because there's always
like any time I'm doing a breath work
there's always like when I'm done doing
or I take my last breath there's always
kind of like a settling in like okay
that's my last breath yeah this is not
for you
this is just true and definitely if I
had like a be a bad posture you're gonna
breathe poorly like and it affects your
physiology a hard core I mean I breathe
from my belly now I used to move from my
chest before but it's definitely
something so as I'm doing not only wim
hof breathing as I'm doing I have like
multiple things throughout the day
especially being at home where I install
and I kind of give these things power I
give myself like okay stand up be be
astute be tall posture
chests out like these these sort of
things so I think a lot of people could
add these to their to their breath work
like a cold showers I do i turn the I
take my regular shower and then at the
end a lot of times what I do there's
this I don't I don't know it's kind of
like weird to explain but you kind of
force the the breath up from the bottom
of your belly right as you thrust down
and you pull in I usually do a lot of
times I'll do thirty of those and then
I'll turn the water to cold
new two minutes of cold and for me I
that's where I insert my sort of like
Tony Robbins like badassery riot like
you know I'm healthy I'm wealthy my eyes
I'm I'm healthy out why am I doing this
cold shower because I do uncomfortable
things cuz I'm not afraid of it and like
you know just this installing of
whatever but at the same time I'm fixing
my posture I'm standing up as tall as I
can I'm pushing my chest out when I go
on runs I'm not just running to burn
calories I'm not just trying to lose
weight I'm running to work on my posture
- because I'm in posture practice I'm in
positive influence practice I think that
this way of thinking like inserting
little breath work and posture work and
whatever into people's daily lives is
going to be pretty important than the
quarantine I think what else could you
say about posture Spencer because I'm
I'm envisioning a lot of people like for
one not having to dress up not like
imagine like your posture just going out
in public like like you just have your
chest more open you're like kind of
proud of the clothes you're wearing
rather than like if you've been wearing
the same pair of sweat pants for three
days you're just all slob when your
hair's messed up you're kind of
shoulders are forward like it's just
kind of a natural thing to think about
think we're all gonna be experiencing a
little bit of the hunching and the
uncomfortable and the not as much upper
body lifting as we're used to so what
what what else could be said about
posture and recommendations there oh
stop sitting so much really you
fix your posture not don't this this now
we need like you want align your
shoulders up with your ears your head
comes back like the classic keyboard
posture this thing which I'm sure we're
all doing way more than usual even
though we already do it a lot is
definitely I mean I'm sure your hips
hurt from setting for your back hurts
like one of the water things it's like
you'd lay down on your stomach
honestly it's right honestly it's a
really good way to fix your posture
isn't just instead of like I'm gonna sit
down and watch this TV show on my phone
lay on your stomach and drive your
elbows into the ground and push your
back flat just now that's the opposite
of this you're opening all the way up
yeah I like also including in that when
you're laying on your stomach because I
do I think I put my my thumb's like
probably around my ribs there and I lift
up but I actually keep my face my chin
tucked and I keep my face looking down
at the ground and so I'm getting a lot
of length the back of my neck here as
I'm pushing I'm pushing flat against the
floor stretching against like almost as
if my heels are being pulled and the top
of my head is being pulled as well but
my I'm facing down so yeah like you said
it creates like a long line I think
that's a good one yeah laying on the
stomach what else we got like for
solutions or why you should get better
posture yes okay well if you look at
your tongue your diaphragm so your mid
chest right below your collarbone and
your hips like like plates yeah they
should all be lying flat on each other
so if your hips are tilted forward and
your ribcage is tilted this way and your
chin is tilted this way which is how
most people stand you're gonna have bad
posture so if you most people their hips
shift forward so it's it looks like
you're sticking their butt out that's
what's happening get this big bend and
the lower back shift them down
controlled contract your abdomen pull
your hips underneath you and then sit
your ribcage while also contracting your
abdomen over your hips and then push
your head back with your chin parallel
to the ground
you should line all these things up and
then that is now which where you should
stand
right yeah I think that's that's good
yeah because I mean and if you want some
testament to this all right let's say if
you have a car you take one tire you
angle it one degree okay that's really
not gonna be a problem today let's give
you a massive problem in a year like you
just are slowly and like all these
little discrepancies in your body that
aren't lining up how they're supposed to
will slowly become like okay if my ankle
mobility is bad so now my left shoulder
hurts like the whole of this is
connected and when you don't pay
attention to it and don't treat it well
it's just gonna break right yes
yeah I think understanding that these
things can be improved to like a you
know just like so many of these things
in this area like where you're working
on yourself your body your posture your
mental health whatever you aren't just
born with one thing and you have to live
with that and we're not a live with that
forever I think it's like you're not
born with bad posture and you have to
have bad posture forever if you're if
you need to open up your physiology and
open up your chest now is a great time
to do it and practice doing it becoming
a way that you're doing it yeah I tell
my clients I'd never accept pain like
one of those things I hate the most is
one like some forty year old woman it's
like my knee hurts that's just the way
it is isn't this what getting olds like
it's like well yeah no no it's not it
doesn't have to be like this unless
they've had like four nurse knee
surgeries and it's like okay it probably
is just like this like you I mean you
just can't accept it like why would you
there's nothing structurally wrong with
you like you just need to figure out
what is wrong we're gonna need at least
try like you the moment you would just
accept these things and oh they can
permanent and my god yeah but I've got
this I've got that like one you can't
you can't just a lot say that this is a
changeable thing like I have bad Bosh or
well you could have your posture if you
wanted like you don't you just doesn't
have to be this way yeah I think we
identify just as much as we identify
with our with our job titles you know we
also identify with our labels to are
like oh I am this I have this I have bad
knees like we'll we'll see how many
times a day we can say it just to
reinforce it you know make sure people
know I think that that now it's just
like
I don't know you got the time start
exploring like okay maybe I do maybe my
knees are bad but maybe they could be a
little bit better maybe I'm not gonna
run climb Kilimanjaro but maybe I can
maybe I can start stretching and I think
stretching is so freaking important
stretching is there's no rules behind
stretching is the thing I think just at
any time when you're at home you've been
working for a few hours you have to set
aside a workout like oh I got a workout
today at this time if you can have that
planned out that's great but you could
also just be I've been working for an
hour in 20 minutes my back's feeling a
little tight I'm gonna lay on the ground
and just aggressively stretch for the
next five minutes and send my breath
around and whenever I think even little
little stretch breaks like that are muy
importante yeah I don't know I do with
the bonus structure but no like just do
it feels good I mean okay I I feel very
oddly about this because part of me as a
personal trainer is like there is a good
way to execute things and there's a bad
way to execute things but I also feel
like you should just do what feels
correct mmm and if it doesn't hurt to
keep doing it so just go with the flow I
mean until you don't know what you need
to do when he starts scratching like you
hit a spotty light that's what this is
fun do you feel like people are
sometimes afraid to explore their own
bodies and these way like they're afraid
to like I I'm afraid of doing it wrong
it's like dude it's just your body just
check it out I'm like whoa you think the
foreign police are gonna come down and
beat you like it's like there's no I
mean there are people have asserted a
bunch of rules but you have to follow
them I don't know might as well to see
what's going on you know it's a lot of
rules he probably don't follow anyways
in your regular life like why are you so
scared of these ones I don't know yeah I
think people are scared of exploring
like their body and like a holistic
sense of general like their mind what
they enjoy it anyway like it's just I'm
comfortable I don't want to do anything
wrong so I'm just going to continue to
be this way if you don't have to
question your beliefs why would you why
would you I do believe that that is not
a I think epicurean says the on the
uninspected life is not worth living
hmm or you might as well like if you're
going to live and not inspect your life
you might as well like what's the
difference in that being dead it's
really none you know like I mean this is
I mean that's what life's about is just
figure out what you like mmm test a
bunch ideas around how you want see what
works for you
like it's so like if your body and your
life is like just a big push board of
buttons you know and you only push like
four or five when before you die what if
like those aren't your favorite buttons
okay like and what if you push one and
don't like it well [__] don't push it
again that's all you got it might as
well go try stuff we define ourselves by
our button pushing yeah you you the
whole board man you could check it all
out and I think that um people who say I
mean everyone to some degree has a
tendency to choose comfort but there's
also the human urge for novelty and you
just gotta mm-hmm
right yeah I get out of the comfort zone
yeah I'm a huge fan and out yeah but I
think that I think a lot of a lot of
finding our age of comfort like
at a time like this is kind of like
choosing dread later like a lot of
comfort is kind of like alcohol right
where you're like almost borrowing a
little bit of happiness from tomorrow
like yeah I can drink a little bit more
it's gonna be a little more fun maybe
I'm gonna like [__] more with my
dumb friends but tomorrow I'm gonna feel
less happy than I would if I don't do
this
you're almost borrowing it so I think
it's almost if you see comfort now as
like okay yeah like I don't necessarily
want to get off off off my butt and turn
off the TV but I think that I know that
the little bit of uncomfort now will pay
off later and it's not borrowing
happiness from from tomorrow it's kind
of adding a little bit of potential
layer of happiness to build off of
tomorrow and this actually brings up
something I kinda want to pick on a
little bit the Internet perception of
what self-care is and then what it
actually is
like everyone's like I'm just
participating yourself care I'm between
this thing but it's obvious like this
thing that is over not even that long of
a term pretty detrimental you know like
when I go get drunk because it's
self-care or I'm gonna just like lay
around and that can be self-care but
it's like there's all these like people
will align like a lot of destructive
pleasurable habits which is self-care or
like blatant can spike buying a bunch of
things I mean these things are not like
what that fix like it wouldn't self care
be like finding something I about
yourself or maybe pursuing one of these
things that doesn't have this pleasure
to this pleasure curve like booze it's
like if drinking is really not self-care
like and I would argue that people are
always are like hedonism is like oh
you're gonna go do a bunch of drugs do
all these things but no because you're
gonna feel greater sadness after this is
done than the happiness is worse so this
is not hedonistic this is not it's not
good and so yeah it's tight it's trying
to bar its hand and Arling something
from tomorrow no I agree I think that
that's important I think that a lot of
people are are why meeting us I don't
know but it's bet that a lot of people
are probably trying to like drinking
their way through this thing
oh I've definitely seen it yeah I mean
but people probably think the way
through their days anyways they're just
now have time to snapchat it right
Wow well I mean I think that's something
if you've I think that taking a look at
the other people around you and saying
like if you're the one you're drinking
like what value are you offering to them
like I I know I've had a I'm bridging on
this on this particular subject but I've
had a lot of good progress with because
I know that I'm easily irritable after a
while with my mom living here so I've
had a lot of progress on reminding
myself like not being self-centered not
being like okay what do I want what do I
want to do like cool like maybe I do
want to get I don't just have example
maybe I wanted to get drunk all day and
then like you know maybe but but instead
I try to think of like how could I be
valuable to my mom like what does my mom
need like because I know that she is
she's older and she's admittedly
a little scared about this whole thing
it's a scary like she doesn't know like
if I get it am I gonna be like really
sick I think she has a prior you know
diabetes these sort of things but so
I've been trying to try to see things
from her view try to like what like what
does she want she wants comfort she
wants to be understood these sort of
things and the the the gap on bridging
was just thinking about like people who
might be like drunk all day when they
could be maybe being more supportive to
the people that are in the same
household as them instead like I said of
trying to focus on what do I want well I
want to get drunk what you could do is
before you even have a drink you could
say what does my mom want like my
mommy's a little comforting like those
sort of things so I guess that's not
super related but that is a gap that you
can that you can correlate yeah
I agree it's not up to me to shame
people for their vices that I don't
share but I also think that it is pretty
destructive if done to extremes I mean
to be honest and it's just
let's just add decision death water I
mean it's just poison about 100 percent
way it's just not like it's just you you
smoke too much weed you just like
cooking a groggy for it did you drink
too much booze you just might die maybe
kiss my back I don't know I think it
affects everybody differently everybody
has their vices so so definitely like I
like if I smoked a ton of weed if
somebody smoked as much we decided and
it made them like sit there on the couch
and like we have vegetarian or
vegetarian via via veg just like you
know not do much it's not positively
affecting their life like if you can't
just be choosing fun and like content
right now if you're able to do a little
bit of these things and they motivate
you like if you're like oh I've been
waiting to clean the garage like I'm
gonna have you know maybe maybe a couple
beers while I clean the garage because
it's gonna make me kind of like House of
fun and dance around while I listen to
music and clean my garage like you
should enjoy your life and you should
add these things into your life to enjoy
it but you shouldn't use these things
these vices as the only way that you
enjoy life yeah I actually have a very
healthy relationship with alcohol I
would like really enjoy it I'm drink a
lot but like it always it's always good
whenever it happens but I feel like like
I was saying earlier like this is a time
where if you have vices they're just
gonna Nick await you so you have nothing
else to do mhm
so I'm sure people are falling to them
honestly I wish that I smoked weed like
consistently because it would make this
so much more tolerable
is this like such a nice introspective
thing and I'm just not used to it so
it's not fun right it's just massively
intense yes yes well hey it's never too
late to start yeah well I honestly don't
want to go on a public to buy weed and
that's kind of where a man I know that's
it I just don't want to go in there and
like transact at all or I will have
those poor guys like just thinking about
like all the people on the other side of
the cash register it's like they're in
such a constant state of fear they're
like I've known do I analyze this person
do I think like I don't know
did I person just coughed before the
handing me the money or Visa Card like
it's it's like a constant state of
everybody who's working right now
obviously but like especially the people
who are like
and next next next like Burger King
workers like all the you know weed
stores alcohol stores all this sort of
thing all the sudden is about all the
dregs of society working the minimum
wage job or the important workers but
all the CEOs are at home in their house
mmm Jeff Bezos making 8 million dollars
an hour say man he is our overlord what
she wasn't he it's just absurd honestly
like the way like just the way things
are or insane to me that's like he I
keep just ending with the sentence like
ha ha we live in a virtual reality video
game uh-huh like in this girl it's
madness you just did the way that things
are is just super [__] weird I wish I
could time-travel then or dud well what
is it I just wait you can just wait in
games it's gonna wait what wait 24 hours
so I want to I do want to end with a
couple more suggestions can you just
give me a couple suggestions of people
that you follow maybe on Instagram
YouTube just like you know not not
necessarily just like kovat advice or
just like self-quarantine advice but
just maybe like I'm gonna go ahead and
say that for everybody ever right now
this is a time to like work on yourself
in some way whether that's mental or
physical or whatever so if you can just
give me anybody that you watch or
consume on any of these apps or anything
that you can recommend to people maybe I
can't check this personnel you got
anything well I'm gonna pull one he's a
fitness guy but he does a lot of like
stoic mindfulness stuff so if you read
through his podcast you don't have to
listen to like the the complex metabolic
hormone ones just like go to the ones
that are obviously like life advices
need the descriptions his name is Jade
Tita he does a podcast called
look at next level human hmm that's a
cool name for a buddy yes yeah he's
great and it's very reasonable I mean he
speaks about complex things like very
well like very clearly and it's very
nice and he just he's just a stoic just
I really enjoy countdown like creating
purpose managing fatigue and mindset in
the gym let's see a lot of it is just um
just like how to live a good life
essentially he actually wrote a book
called next level human and it's so
basically a stoic book right yeah so
that's what I like cool I try to I try
to pick one that you don't ingest so we
didn't overlap what about you yeah no
yeah I haven't checked that one out I'm
definitely gonna have check that one out
what about me actually didn't priorly
plan this I'm gonna say I think they'll
probably suggested this before but I'll
just reiterate Tom bile you be ILY EQ
and his elite his wife Lisa while you as
well
they his thing is just like when he was
younger he's actually from Tacoma
originally but when he was younger he
was just like dude I'm just like a poor
dumb kid from from Tacoma and he just
wanted to be smart so he went on he went
on to found co-founder quest nutrition
he kind of like built his own like mine
no I know this guy yeah yeah so and then
from there he has a show on YouTube that
I'm suggesting and I did some podcast
for him it's called impact Theory he has
a bunch of like subdivisions of it but
like dude this guy he he's like intense
like he is it's like good like listening
like he hypes you up with his energy but
he's also just like he's always going
like every day he's posting at least one
new thing he's got he's been doing this
for years and years he's like a
motivational speaker
I think he's another he's just another
good one we can like read the title or
glance in the description of any of his
new stuff old stuff and it'll just you
know apply to like the time and yeah I
think it's just like I kind of like wit
like you do Spencer I often have the
podcast kind of just playing in the
background a lot of times I'm I'm fairly
fixated on it but I
no podcasts and YouTube things that you
don't really have to watch which is of
many of them you can put them on this
speaker or that speaker or this room or
get a portable speaker or have it in
your headphones like just kind of
inserting these into again maybe it's
not super healthy to be doing all the
time make sure you do find some silence
but I feel like as far as conditions go
now where people are like okay I've sat
at home and watched Netflix a lot and
I've set on the couch from now my body
hurts like what's what else what other
options are there to do with life like
how else do people do at home life and I
think this is a good solution is you
know maybe go to youtube or podcast and
find one that you like that you really
are like this is nice that I'm spending
my time this way you know I saw I don't
know if I have any other YouTube
channels go check out
yeah oh man yeah I have quite a few I'm
always like dropping them I think that I
think that the thing about YouTube men
the the data the the data that they have
on you is is weirdly a nice positive
thing like they can start suggesting
some like okay I'm watching stoic
philosophy for example and then they'll
start suggesting like some clips from
people who usually upload that sort of
content that you've never heard before
or like oh you like this so you likely
like this or maybe like this in on
YouTube when you start hitting like we
start getting subscribe like all these
things whatever you start suggesting
more content that you might find better
so if you're consuming a bunch of
Kardashians it's gonna suggest more
Kardashian [__] but if you're consuming
this good stuff it's gonna be like okay
this is the type of content that you
want to consume you'll feed it more to
you and it'll actually be things that
you enjoy it's not like this is gonna be
a work project where you're like oh I
don't watch more podcast or listens to
more [__] well if you if you think about
it like that it will be though so think
about adjoining it yeah really yeah like
I will the Eckhart Tolle has a YouTube
channel oh yeah you like a cartel of
course dude yeah his I wasn't saying
that like I was shocked or anything I
don't know that but a dude his his story
is interested can he remember off the
top of your head he had I'm not fully
your memory but he had tried to commit
suicide and he I'm like an awakening
instead did you hear about this I
believe so yeah yeah super found now I'm
totally gonna like wanna go like relearn
it
have you read the power of now the power
of now I'm not read no I I'm you should
read it I think you might not need it
you can't already do this thing but it's
a good book right no I have a my friend
JC Randall she you said that it was like
one of the books that like when she read
it it like like changed the way that she
thought about things and I was listening
to him on YouTube is pretty
he's a very he looks so much different
than I thought he was gonna look he's a
very like he's just looked he's just an
interesting looking guy I know yeah yeah
he's hard to figure out but it's so
interesting like it's a in learning like
listening to all these different types
of people with their different accents
and their different demeanor their
different way of speaking I feel like it
like also just like gives you this level
of patience for new types of people too
and in a strange way too cuz I just just
think of the way the he talks he's very
like breath out he's very just as a lot
of like kind of like enlightened masters
seem to be it seems like they're never
holding anything in they're always just
kind of on the out-breath as they're
talking yeah enlightened masters yeah
and also I mean I can be really do bored
star reading yeah
so reading what would you read when you
were younger what was your like when you
were I love fantasy I love fantasy like
me personally but as an adult I read
pretty much like mindfulness books and
like political theory because I'm a nerd
who's pushed my glasses back good okay
that's about it yeah so I've actually
recently I've had this like flirting
thing in my stomach where I'm like Jake
damn it just do it like where I because
I used to read a lot of fantasy when I
was younger but then like the last two
years when I started like reading again
it's just been you know self-help
meditation stoicism Buddhism like all
these sort of just just learning more
self-actualization really sort of
corners of reading but I've been
thinking more that I want to actually
reread some books that I read as a child
there was this book called the far side
of the mountain it was like this dudette
like went out to the woods and he had
like a so he's like a teenager Nana
sound like peregrine falcon it was pet
but uh and then fantasy I used to read
to that was like but yeah I've been
thinking I won like maybe dit more back
into that so if I feel like I'm like
working too much I think I'm gonna keep
that on the back burner of like you know
what I'm gonna order like a fantasy on
audible
book or a story that I used to like
before instead of like making it all
self-help work which i think is
important too it's nice it's just like a
playground for the mind you know like -
I just played playthrough The Witcher a
game I've been waiting to play with like
five there's ice to just like turn this
and just like enjoy a story that it's
not it's not set here so there's no like
reward implications it's just like
here's fairytale land go enjoy it and
that is pretty pure compared to what we
actually have in real world right cool
man I agree I think we should we should
likely wrap this up I having some weird
cut out but I appreciate you doing this
I know it's like weird I know it's not
like as great as being in person
obviously it's hard like you know like
you can't have as much banter yeah
because it's kind of like the second
that you notice that they're talking or
if you're like oh [__] I've been talking
too much and they don't really have a
place to interject it's a different type
but I think that it is valuable content
and I hope that you know some listeners
were able to like get some sort of like
oh maybe I'm gonna do this full but
differently now that times are are
everlasting in this in this manner so I
appreciate you Spencer thanks for didn't
let's do it again thanks for having me
on my boy yeah my friend cool sounds
good listeners have a good rest of your
day please focus on your posture and all
these other things that we mentioned and
Spencer and I will be back probably soon
sometime